Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Tibet), 1958 February; 10 (Box 1547)
    - HORSES WIN OKAY: Lowell Thomas and party followed the ancient and treacherous caravan route from Sikkim over the high Himalayas to get to forbidden Tibet, which is the backdrop for the fourth installment of High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast over the CBS television network Tuesday, February 25th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. Thomas fondles his equine carrier which is most dependable form of transportation since Tibetans absolutely forbid travel by air, car, or even by carriage, or cart. As far as transportation is concerned, Tibet is a country without a wheel, 3
    - Note: [press release] HORSES WIN OKAY: Lowell Thomas and party followed the ancient and treacherous caravan route from Sikkim over the high Himalayas to get to forbidden Tibet, which is the backdrop for the fourth installment of High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast over the CBS television network Tuesday, February 25th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. Thomas fondles his equine carrier which is most dependable form of transportation since Tibetans absolutely forbid travel by air, car, or even by carriage, or cart. As far as transportation is concerned, Tibet is a country without a wheel, 4
    - AND THE RAINS CAME: Lowell Thomas and son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., take breather on perilous 24-day trek over Himalayas to the forbidden land of Tibet which serves as the theme of Episode No. 4 of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast on CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST under the sponsorship of the United Motors Service and Delco-Remy division of General Motors. The two are wearing regulation U.S. navy foul-weather gear because it rained practically all through the trip, 5
    - Note: [press release] AND THE RAINS CAME: Lowell Thomas and son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., take breather on perilous 24-day trek over Himalayas to the forbidden land of Tibet which serves as the theme of Episode No. 4 of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which will be colorcast on CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST under the sponsorship of the United Motors Service and Delco-Remy division of General Motors. The two are wearing regulation U.S. navy foul-weather gear because it rained practically all through the trip, 6
    - ROYAL WELCOME: Among the first westerners permitted to penetrate the forbidden land of Tibet, Lowell Thomas, Jr. (left) and his illustrious father, Lowell Thomas, Sr. (right) received a royal welcome form the Dalai Lama, legendary ruler of the strange country which isolated itself from civilization for centuries. Here, they pose with gifts in the Dalai Lama's fantastic 1000-room castle in Lhasa, Tibet's capital, which will be highlighted in Episode No. 4 (Tibet) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" on CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 7
    - Note: [press release] ROYAL WELCOME: Among the first westerners permitted to penetrate the forbidden land of Tibet, Lowell Thomas, Jr. (left) and his illustrious father, Lowell Thomas, Sr. (right) received a royal welcome form the Dalai Lama, legendary ruler of the strange country which isolated itself from civilization for centuries. Here, they pose with gifts in the Dalai Lama's fantastic 1000-room castle in Lhasa, Tibet's capital, which will be highlighted in Episode No. 4 (Tibet) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" on CBS-TV, Tuesday, February 25th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 8
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Australian Outback), 1958 March; 11 (Box 1547)
    - OUTBACK BACKGROUND: A good idea of the roughness of the Australian Outback terrain which is featured in the fifth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color on CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) can be obtained from this photo showing trucks of the Lowell Thomas expedition trying to find traveling space. Most sections of the vast desert, however, can be traversed only by camel. The Thomas troupe spent months in this forsaken land looking for the bones of the lost Australian-American explorer, Harold Bell Lasseter. The search was successful. The Lasseter story is the subject of the fifth "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 1
    - Note: [press release] OUTBACK BACKGROUND: A good idea of the roughness of the Australian Outback terrain which is featured in the fifth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color on CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) can be obtained from this photo showing trucks of the Lowell Thomas expedition trying to find traveling space. Most sections of the vast desert, however, can be traversed only by camel. The Thomas troupe spent months in this forsaken land looking for the bones of the lost Australian-American explorer, Harold Bell Lasseter. The search was successful. The Lasseter story is the subject of the fifth "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, 2
    - [2 copies] LOWELL THOMAS AND AUSSIE ABORIGINE EXAMINE SACRED TRIBAL "DREAMING STONE" IN DESERT: Lowell Thomas and Nosepeg, an aborigine of Australia's Pitjinjara tribe, inspect an ancient "dreaming stone" along the trail of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. On these rocks, the history of the pre-historic tribes can be traced by aborigine medicine men. Near this spot Thomas's 26-member expedition solved the 28-year-old mystery of the disappearance of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter, 3
    - Note: [press release] LOWELL THOMAS AND AUSSIE ABORIGINE EXAMINE SACRED TRIBAL "DREAMING STONE" IN DESERT: Lowell Thomas and Nosepeg, an aborigine of Australia's Pitjinjara tribe, inspect an ancient "dreaming stone" along the trail of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. On these rocks, the history of the pre-historic tribes can be traced by aborigine medicine men. Near this spot Thomas's 26-member expedition solved the 28-year-old mystery of the disappearance of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter, 4
    - AUSTRALIAN ABORIGINE MAKES ANIMAL TRACKS IN RED SAND OF "HIGH ADVENTURE" TRAIL: An aborigine of the Pindabee tribe scratches animal tracks in the red sand of the Australian Outback as film director lee Robinson (wearing sun hat) watcher, during the shooting of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM EST) Monday, March 24. On the program, which travels through some of the world's most uncharted territory, Thomas and his expedition discover the long-lost grave of soldier of fortune Harold Bell Lasseter, 5
    - Note: [press release] AUSTRALIAN ABORIGINE MAKES ANIMAL TRACKS IN RED SAND OF "HIGH ADVENTURE" TRAIL: An aborigine of the Pindabee tribe scratches animal tracks in the red sand of the Australian Outback as film director lee Robinson (wearing sun hat) watcher, during the shooting of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM EST) Monday, March 24. On the program, which travels through some of the world's most uncharted territory, Thomas and his expedition discover the long-lost grave of soldier of fortune Harold Bell Lasseter, 6
    - ROCK AND TWO ROLLERS: Deep in Central Australia, Lowell Thomas (left) and Director Lee Robinson discuss next move in filming the fifth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) which deals with the hunt for the body of Harold Bell Lasseter, Australian-American explorer who was lost in 1931 while trying to relocate a fabulous gold reef in the rugged Outback country. Behind the duo is the world's largest single rock called Ayres Rock. It is 1100 feet high and over 8 miles around the base, 7
    - Note: [press release] ROCK AND TWO ROLLERS: Deep in Central Australia, Lowell Thomas (left) and Director Lee Robinson discuss next move in filming the fifth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color, CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) which deals with the hunt for the body of Harold Bell Lasseter, Australian-American explorer who was lost in 1931 while trying to relocate a fabulous gold reef in the rugged Outback country. Behind the duo is the world's largest single rock called Ayres Rock. It is 1100 feet high and over 8 miles around the base, 8
    - LOWELL THOMAS AND AUSTRALIAN DROVER SWAP YARNS ALONG "HIGH ADVENTURE" TRAIL: Lowell Thomas (1) and Matt Savage, Central Australia's oldest drover, swap yarns along the trail to "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. In the middle of the sprawling Australian continent, where cattle stations (ranches) range up to 9,000,00 acres, Thomas and a 26-member expedition trek into the untamed Outback to solve a desert mystery which had existed for 28 years-the disappearance of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter, 9
    - Note: [press release] LOWELL THOMAS AND AUSTRALIAN DROVER SWAP YARNS ALONG "HIGH ADVENTURE" TRAIL: Lowell Thomas (1) and Matt Savage, Central Australia's oldest drover, swap yarns along the trail to "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. In the middle of the sprawling Australian continent, where cattle stations (ranches) range up to 9,000,00 acres, Thomas and a 26-member expedition trek into the untamed Outback to solve a desert mystery which had existed for 28 years-the disappearance of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter, 10
    - THE DEVIL YOU CARE: Lowell Thomas is entranced by a strange species of lizard called "mountain devils" while color-filming the fifth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) which deals with life in the desolate Outback country in Central Australia. Former themes in the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" series, sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, were New Guinea, the North pole, Africa and Tibet, 11
    - Note: [press release] THE DEVIL YOU CARE: Lowell Thomas is entranced by a strange species of lizard called "mountain devils" while color-filming the fifth installment of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS-TV, Monday, March 24th, 8:00-9:00 p.m., EST) which deals with life in the desolate Outback country in Central Australia. Former themes in the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" series, sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy division of General Motors, were New Guinea, the North pole, Africa and Tibet, 12
    - END TO A 28-YEAR-OLD MYSTERY: In the middle of the vast Australian Outback, Dr. John Quinn, Lucky Harris and Lowell Thomas (left to right) inspect the remains of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter during the climax of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. When Thomas and his crew found the bones of Lasseter in a lonely red-sand grave in the Petermann Range, it ended a 28-year-old mystery about the fate of the Aussie-American soldier of fortune who vanished in 1930, 13
    - Note: [press release] END TO A 28-YEAR-OLD MYSTERY: In the middle of the vast Australian Outback, Dr. John Quinn, Lucky Harris and Lowell Thomas (left to right) inspect the remains of gold-hunter Harold Bell Lasseter during the climax of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television, 8:00-9:00 PM, EST) Monday, March 24. When Thomas and his crew found the bones of Lasseter in a lonely red-sand grave in the Petermann Range, it ended a 28-year-old mystery about the fate of the Aussie-American soldier of fortune who vanished in 1930, 14
    - [Lowell Thomas and his crew filming in the Australian Outback], 15
    - [Three men in the Australian Outback], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man sitting outside their tent in the Australian Outback], 17
  Box 1548
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Tiger Hunt), 1958 April; 1 (Box 1548)
    - GOOD LISTENER----Lowell Thomas (right) takes some good advice from John Grisham [Jack Girsham?], who knows his way around the rugged country of northeast India, during filming in color of sixth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" which will be televised on CBS network Saturday, April 19, from 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST. Grisham [Girsham?], carrying elephant rifle, was a most valued scout with the famous Merrill's Marauders during that unit's tussles with the Japanese in Burma in World War II. A hunt for wild elephants and man-eating tigers features this particular edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 1
    - Note: [press release] GOOD LISTENER----Lowell Thomas (right) takes some good advice from John Grisham [Jack Girsham?], who knows his way around the rugged country of northeast India, during filming in color of sixth edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" which will be televised on CBS network Saturday, April 19, from 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST. Grisham [Girsham?], carrying elephant rifle, was a most valued scout with the famous Merrill's Marauders during that unit's tussles with the Japanese in Burma in World War II. A hunt for wild elephants and man-eating tigers features this particular edition of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with John Grisham, tiger hunter], 3
    - BUILDING A BETTER TRAP----Natives in Assam Province of northeast India are in the process of constructing huge trap for man-eating tiger that has been attacking fellow villagers. Over 500 spearmen and "beaters" participated in the hunt for the striped beast which is featured in the next edition in color of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS-TV network, Saturday, April 19, 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST). Other stirring sequence in the hour-long show depicts capture and training of wild elephants. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 4
    - Note: [press release] BUILDING A BETTER TRAP----Natives in Assam Province of northeast India are in the process of constructing huge trap for man-eating tiger that has been attacking fellow villagers. Over 500 spearmen and "beaters" participated in the hunt for the striped beast which is featured in the next edition in color of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS-TV network, Saturday, April 19, 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST). Other stirring sequence in the hour-long show depicts capture and training of wild elephants. "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 5
    - POINTS THE WAY----Noted film director Willard Van Dyke points out next scene in action during filming of sixth episode (Tiger Hunt in India) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color over CBS-TV network, Saturday, April 19, 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST). Lowell Thomas and his production crew spent more than three months in the jungles of Assam Province in northeast India photographing live capture of a vicious man-eating tiger by 500 natives. Also to be seen in the film is round-up of wild elephants for conversion to domestic use. Mahouts on elephants in background actually "lasso" the wild pachyderms in same fashion as Western cowboys rope steers. Van Dyke won much acclaim for his production and direction of the documentary film, "The City", 6
    - Note: [press release] POINTS THE WAY----Noted film director Willard Van Dyke points out next scene in action during filming of sixth episode (Tiger Hunt in India) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (in color over CBS-TV network, Saturday, April 19, 9:00 to 10:00 p.m., EST). Lowell Thomas and his production crew spent more than three months in the jungles of Assam Province in northeast India photographing live capture of a vicious man-eating tiger by 500 natives. Also to be seen in the film is round-up of wild elephants for conversion to domestic use. Mahouts on elephants in background actually "lasso" the wild pachyderms in same fashion as Western cowboys rope steers. Van Dyke won much acclaim for his production and direction of the documentary film, "The City", 7
    - Mounting a machan to spend a night on a platform in a tree hoping to get a shot at man-eating tiger on a tea plantation at the edge of the jungle at the foot of the Himalayas in Assam in 1958. At the foot of the ladder, Jack Girsham, famous hunter of maneaters - - half Burmese and half Scot, 8
    - Note: Mounting a machan to spend a night on a platform in a tree hoping to get a shot at man-eating tiger on a tea plantation at the edge of the jungle at the foot of the Himalayas in Assam in 1958. At the foot of the ladder, Jack Girsham, famous hunter of maneaters - - half Burmese and half Scot, 9
    - "HOLD THAT TIGER!"; Indian spearmen (members of the Tiger Catching Society of Jamaguri) gather about a very dead tiger at the end of the trail of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television Network, 9:00-10:00 PM, EST) Saturday, April 19.; The big cat, punctured by a dozen native spears, was reportedly the same Royal Bengal tiger which had killed 35 Indian tea plantation workers. The killings ceased after Lowell Thomas hired more than 500 native spearmen to track the cat, 10
    - Note: [press release] "HOLD THAT TIGER!"; Indian spearmen (members of the Tiger Catching Society of Jamaguri) gather about a very dead tiger at the end of the trail of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television Network, 9:00-10:00 PM, EST) Saturday, April 19.; The big cat, punctured by a dozen native spears, was reportedly the same Royal Bengal tiger which had killed 35 Indian tea plantation workers. The killings ceased after Lowell Thomas hired more than 500 native spearmen to track the cat, 11
    - "A NOSE FOR FOOD"; One of the baby elephants to be seen on "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television Network, 9:00-10:00 PM, EST) Saturday, April 19, shows a real "nose for food" as associate film director Bob Young does the feeding.; Televiewers will follow Thomas and his film crew as they chase wild elephants along the Northeast border of India. Another segment of "High Adventure" involves a hunt for a man-killing Bengal tiger, 12
    - Note: [press release] "A NOSE FOR FOOD"; One of the baby elephants to be seen on "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" (CBS Television Network, 9:00-10:00 PM, EST) Saturday, April 19, shows a real "nose for food" as associate film director Bob Young does the feeding.; Televiewers will follow Thomas and his film crew as they chase wild elephants along the Northeast border of India. Another segment of "High Adventure" involves a hunt for a man-killing Bengal tiger, 13
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting on an elephant], 14
    - [Man filming an elephant], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in front of an elephant], 16
  - Subject files: High Adventure with Lowell Thomas (Morocco), 1958 May; 2 (Box 1548)
    - WON'T YOU DANCE WITH ME?; Dancing girl in the fabulous Moroccan town of Marrakech gives Lowell Thomas basic instructions in a native dance while the famous American explorer and producer was in the northwest African country shooting scenes in color for the seventh installment (Morocco) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas", (CBS-TV, Wednesday, May 28th. 10:00-11:00 p.m., EDST). Thomas introduces the mad dance of the Marrakech houris is one segment of the show which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 1
    - Note: [press release] WON'T YOU DANCE WITH ME?; Dancing girl in the fabulous Moroccan town of Marrakech gives Lowell Thomas basic instructions in a native dance while the famous American explorer and producer was in the northwest African country shooting scenes in color for the seventh installment (Morocco) of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas", (CBS-TV, Wednesday, May 28th. 10:00-11:00 p.m., EDST). Thomas introduces the mad dance of the Marrakech houris is one segment of the show which is sponsored by the United Motors System and Delco-Remy Division of General Motors, 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and his crew in Morocco], 3
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 4
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure"in Morocco], 5
    - [Various photos of people dancing in Morocco taken from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure], 6
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 7
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 8
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 9
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 10
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 11
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 12
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 13
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 14
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 15
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 16
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 17
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 18
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas filming during his "High Adventure" in Morocco], 19
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 20
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 21
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 22
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 23
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 24
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas with the people of Morocco], 25
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 26
    - [Various photos on the set of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 27
    - [Various photos from on the set of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 28
    - [Various photos of Moroccan people on the set of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure"], 29
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 30
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 31
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 32
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas during his "High Adventure" in Morocco], 33
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 34
    - [Various photos from Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 35
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 36
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 37
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 38
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 39
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 40
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 41
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 42
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 43
    - [Various photos of Lowell Thomas's "High Adventure" in Morocco], 44